<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 01:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 01:31:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>

    
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Inject, And How to Protect</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/06/03/technical7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/06/03/technical7</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Structured Query Language (SQL) is a language that allows users and web applications to interact with a database. Any time a user enters input, such as a name or password, a SQL command is enacted which enters the input into a database or matches the input to stored data. A technique called SQL injection makes it frighteningly easy for hackers to exploit SQL commands so that they can infiltrate databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before addressing how SQL injection occurs, it is important to explain the role of SQL in properly functioning web applications. Certain SQL queries are executed whenever a legitimate function is triggered. For example, let’s say that a returning user named John Smith enters his username and password. The web page would send the following SQL command to the database when John hits send. The SQL command would then match the username and password against the stored combination:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;SELECT id
FROM logins
WHERE username=’JohnSmith’
AND password=’1234”;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if the web page isn’t properly coded to protect against SQL attacks? A hacker may  inject additional SQL commands to retrieve stored values. This is made possible because the fields available for user input permit SQL commands to pass through and query the database directly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if a SQL injecter typed the following on an improperly coded webpage, they would be logged into the account because the OR clause is true:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;SELECT id
FROM logins
WHERE username=&amp;#39;’JohnSmith’&amp;#39;
AND password=&amp;#39;password&amp;#39; OR &amp;#39;x&amp;#39;=&amp;#39;x&amp;#39;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most common ways that hackers discover vulnerable web pages is through Google dorks, which are search queries that finds websites meeting the parameters of the advanced query you input. Examples of dorks you can use to find vulnerable sites include inurl:pageid=, inurl:staff_id=, etc.  After going to one of the sites that appear in the search, a hacker would then enter an apostrophe at the end of the URL. If the page returs a SQL error, it is vulnerable. A hacker would determine the amount of columns and rows by entering a URL along the lines of: website/index.php?catid=1 order by 1. They would then increase the numbers one by one until they arrive at an error. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQL injection attacks like this have become popular since all an attacker needs is a web browser, an understanding of SQL, and the ability to guess the name of fields. Apps like Havij have even been developed to facilitate SQL injection attacks. Because of the ease with which SQL injections occur, the Web Application Security Consortium reported that 9% of total hacking incidents in 2006 were due to this technique. This is terrifying. Credit card information, passwords to personal accounts, and other important data are readily available to SQL injecters on web pages that are not properly coded. Security firm Acunetix estimates that 50% of the web pages it tested faced such a risk. In fact, Yahoo, LinkedIn, PBS, the CIA, and Sony Pictures have all been victims of SQL injection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have addressed how SQL injection works, let’s consider how an organization can protect against SQL injection. Firewalls and similar mechanisms alone aren’t sufficient. Automated web vulnerability scanners crawl a website and check for SQL injection vulnerabilities. They will specify which scripts are vulnerable so you can fix the code. Dynamic scripting languages like ASP, .NET, PHP and CGI are especially at risk. A database could also be set to restrict to certain commands only. User input must be filtered as well. For example, only email addresses that include @ should pass. These precautionary measures are essential. Otherwise, your credit card number could be in someone else’s hands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocs, Procs, and Lambdas...oh my!</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/29/technical6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/29/technical6</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;blocks&quot;&gt;Blocks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blocks are bits of code that can be executed and can be defined with either the keywords do and end or with {}. We have worked a lot with blocks so far in Dev Bootcamp because many methods take a block. For example, in &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;array.each {|x| x*2}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anything in the curly brackets is a block that is passed to the method. Unlike a method, though, the block we define will only be called once and in the context of the array we are iterating over. The block appears just long enough to do something for “each”, then disappears. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also possible to transfer control from a calling method to a block and back again using the yield keyword. Here is an example of what that would look like. When the block_test method is called, yield outputs anything that is inside the curly brackets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-29at101312PM_zps3ab7bab2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to realize that blocks are one of very few things in Ruby that are not objects. Let me say that again: blocks are NOT objects. What if we wanted to save a block as an object? That’s where procs and lambdas come in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;procs&quot;&gt;Procs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A proc is an object that stores a block so that you can call it whenever you’d like without having to rewrite it. It is similar to a method, yet it isn’t bound to an object since it IS an object itself. You can output the result of a proc with the .call method or pass a proc to a method. Procs often look similar to methods. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of calling a proc with .call:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-29at101659PM_zpsbad143d0.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of passing a proc to a method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-29at101740PM_zps8362d71c.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lambda&quot;&gt;Lambda&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lambdas, which are like nameless methods, are similar to procs. lambda{puts “hello”} is the same as Proc.new {puts “hello”}.Unlike procs, lambdas check the number of arguments passed to it and will throw an error if you pass it the wrong number of arguments. Also, when a lambda returns, it passes control back to the calling method, while a proc returns immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Codecademy lesson on blocks, procs, and lambdas is very helpful, so if you want to learn more, I would suggest going through it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/courses/ruby-beginner-en-L3ZCI/0/1/&quot; title=&quot;here.&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereotype Threat</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/29/cultural6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/29/cultural6</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stereotype threat is the risk of behaving in line with a stereotype about one’s group when the group is brought to one’s attention. Being aware of the stereotype creates an anxiety that can impair performance, thus resulting in a self-fulfilling prophecy in which the stereotype is filled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This phenomena came to light in 1995 when Claude Steele and Joshua Aronson found that having students check off their race on an SAT test led to  African American students performing worse than Caucasian students, while African American students performed equivalently when race was not checked off. This perhaps unconsciously triggered the inaccurate stereotype that African Americans are less intelligent, which in turn led to students performing in such a way that the stereotype was enforced. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequent research found that stereotype threat doesn’t just occur in standardized testing. It occurs in athletics, academic settings, and many other situations. The mere presence of other people can induce it. For instance, research by Inzlicht et al found that women who took a mathematics exam along with two other women got 70% of the answers right, while women who took a mathematics exam in the presence of two men got an average score of 55%. The salience of gender reminded the women that women are stereotyped as being less intelligent than men in the latter case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frightening research published within the past few weeks expresses a similar issue in which people are likely to treat others in line with the stereotypes of their group. A study by Milkman et al found that professors are likelier to respond to inquiries from students who are white males than to any other group. Even female professors were likelier to respond to males. Some of the professors may have consciously avoided responding to non-white-male students, but it is likelier that most were not aware that they were doing this. The stereotype that white males are the most intelligent group likely led to an unconscious preference for responding to members of this group. This in turn can lead to greater self-consciousness in the groups who did not receive a response, further inducing the self-fulfulling prophecy of stereotype threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consequences of stereotype threat include decreased performance, internal attributions for failure, distancing oneself from the stereotyped group, and altered career goals. These are serious problems. So how can we address them? I believe the best way to combat stereotype threat is to first educate people about it. If people are aware that they are being primed by factors that they may not be aware of, they may be able to avoid responding to the stereotype threat. It is also important to be aware of triggers and eliminate them. For example, SAT test designers should not have students check off their race. It would be impossible to remove all triggers, however, as they are often unconscious or difficult to eradicate, as in the example where women took a math exam in the presence of all men. The more triggers that are removed, though, the better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Now That's Classy</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/22/technical5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/22/technical5</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ruby is an object-oriented language, meaning it uses classes and objects to represent concepts. Classes are template for objects. They include a collection of variables representing internal state and methods that operate on that state. Some built-in classes include String, Integer, Time, Array, and Range. Objects are single instances of a class. For example, “I am a string” is an object of the String class. If you write “I am a string”..upcase, you are calling the upcase method that is defined in the String class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at a more complex example, where we will create a Family class that defines properties and methods that all families have in common. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-22at72903PM_zps4d90a3fc.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;instance-variables&quot;&gt;Instance Variables:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The @ symbol in front of our features (last_name, address) indicate that they are instance variables. Instance variables, which are an object’s variables, last as long as an object does and can be called by any instance method of the object, not just the method it is defined in. Conversely, variables with a local scope (those without a symbol in front of them) only interact with the method they are defined in. We can also have a class variable, indicated by two @@ symbols, which are available to any instance of a class. If we called Family.describe, the string “Family is important” would be outputted. There are also global variables, indicated by a $ symbol, which are available anywhere in a program. Global variables are not common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;attribute-accesor&quot;&gt;Attribute accesor:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because instance variables are only accessible to instance methods and not the outside world, we have to define reader and writer methods, or getters and setters, to expose an object’s instance variables and let a user set them outside the class definition. To do this, we write attr_reader, attr_writer, or attr_accessor, followed by the instance variable names as symbols preceded by a colon, at the top of a class definition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve touched on instance variables and getters and setters, let’s go back to our example and create a Johnson_Family object with its last_name and address specified in the parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-22at72908PM_zpsd8605a82.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because introduce is a method defined in the Family class, we can call it on Johnson_Family like this: Johnson_Family.introduce. This would output “We are the Johnson family”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inheritance&quot;&gt;Inheritance:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we wanted Johnson_Family to have certain features that other families don’t have? For example, let’s say Johnson_Family is a military family and we want to specify what base they live on. We don’t want military_base to be a feature of all Family objects, but we want it to be a feature of some. We could create a new subclass, Military_Family, which inherits all the properties of the parent class Family but which also has features of its own. Then, when we create a new instance of Military_Family, the object will have not only a military_base feature but also a last_name and address. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the “&amp;lt;” symbol below lets Military_Family inherit all the properties of the Family class. Super indicates that we are asking the parent of the current object to invoke a method of the same name. Note that a class can only inherit from a single class at a time (i.e. it can inherit from a class that inherited from a class that inherited from a class, but not from multiple classes at once).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-22at72913PM_zps20b7729d.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would then instantiate Johnson_Family like this: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-22at72920PM_zps570eea69.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you know the basics of classes and objects in Ruby. For further exploration, check out modules, mixins, and private/public/protected methods. Goodbye for now…“class” is no longer in session.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy and Technology</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/22/cultural5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/22/cultural5</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How many times have you tried to pour your heart out to someone only to find that they would not stop playing with their iPhone? While technology has in many ways enhanced human relationships, it has also made it more challenging to maintain empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, a 2011 study at the University of Michigan suggests that technology has contributed to decreased empathy. The research found that today’s college students score 40% lower on tests of empathy than students in past decades. While various factors may play a role, it is hypothesized that the prevalence of social media contributes to this problem. Even though it may be easier to meet people online, social media may distract us from maintaining relationships offline. As one of the psychologists who conducted the study explains, “The ease of having ‘friends’ online might make people more likely to just tune out when they don’t feel like responding to others’ problems, a behavior that could carry over offline.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, a study by Anderson et al in 2010 demonstrated a causal link between exposure to violent videogames and desensitization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that it is not technology in of itself that has resulted in this decrease in empathy. It is the manner and extent to which technology is engaged. A study by Greitemeyer and Osswald in 2010 found that playing prosocial video games actually increases prosocial cognitions and behavior as well as decreases aggressive cognitions. Also, when social media is used in moderation and at the appropriate times, it can make it easier to stay in touch with loved ones. The key to addressing the problem of technology resulting in decreased empathy is thus to build videogames with a more prosocial aim and for people to be more aware of how dependent they are on technology. So the next time you feel like playing Candy Crush while you are having dinner with your family, ask how their days were instead.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inject...And Not the Needle Kind</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/16/technical4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/16/technical4</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I learned about an awesome Ruby method this week. So awesome that I have to share it. That method is Enumerable#inject. When I first started learning Ruby, I did a bunch of exercises that involved writing loops and .each iterators to add every element in an array together, then return the sum of all the elements. This required a large block of code. Here is an example of how such code looked using a while loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-16at42459PM_zpsb0dbc8f2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of how such code would look using an each iterator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-16at42452PM_zps8a277a99.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, I discovered inject, which makes it possible to do this using just ONE LINE OF CODE! Inject is a method in the Enumerable module, which is a set of methods to traverse, search through and manipulate collections. The inject method takes a collection and reduces it to a single value, such as a sum, product, or difference of values. You can even use inject to find the longest string in an array or to convert an array into a hash.Synonyms for inject include reduce, fold, accumulate, and compress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s happening in the code below is inject is storing values in a block variable called memo, then returning the total that is in memo. You can call memo anything you’d like, but it is common practice to call it memo. Note the argument passed to inject is the initial value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/ScreenShot2014-05-16at42509PM_zps0bcd4894.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hallerandhug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/line-divider.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflict</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/16/cultural4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/16/cultural4</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;discuss-a-time-you-had-an-emotional-conflict-with-someone-what-was-it-about-what-happened&quot;&gt;Discuss a time you had an emotional conflict with someone. What was it about? What happened?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t remember the last time I had an emotional conflict with anyone other than in my love life (but that would be too personal 
to talk about here, now wouldn’t that? :-))  Yet I do have an emotional conflict with myself from time to time when I don’t feel I am doing something as well as I should be. The instance that comes to mind is when I applied for an early admission medical
school program my freshman year of college. When I didn’t get in, it initially made me question my worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-was-the-source-of-the-conflict&quot;&gt;What was the source of the conflict?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conflict stemmed from my perfectionism and occasionally being unrealistic in my expectations for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-did-you-handle-that-conflict&quot;&gt;How did you handle that conflict?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My behavior initially fell along the “Attack Self” part of the Compass of Shame. I ultimately realized that the rejection turned out to be one of the best things that happened to me. I had planned on becoming a doctor since I was a kid, so this was the first time that I took a step back and questioned whether this the right path for me. This period of introspection made me realize that medicine was not in fact my calling. I became extremely thankful for the rejection, and decided that from then on I would view situations like that as learning experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-your-actions-make-the-conflict-better-or-worse&quot;&gt;Did your actions make the conflict better or worse?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being so hard on myself didn’t really change anything, which was a part of the lesson for me. All I was able to do was continue to try my best at anything I applied myself to in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-you-could-go-back-what-would-you-do-differently-if-anything&quot;&gt;If you could go back, what would you do differently, if anything?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t have been so hard on myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-did-you-learn-from-this-experience&quot;&gt;What did you learn from this experience?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned that sometimes rejections turn out to be blessings in disguise. I also learned to distinguish between situations that are under our control and those that are beyond our control. The effort and work that went into the essays I submitted for the program were under my control but the ultimate decision was not and there was nothing I could do to change this. Thinking of the Serenity Prayer helps ground me when I lose sight of the distinction: “Grant me the serenity to accept the things I cannot change, the courage to change the things I can, and the wisdom to know the difference.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hallerandhug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/line-divider.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why JavaScript is So Popular</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/08/technical3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/08/technical3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is a client-side scripting language, meaning that it is primarily run as part of a user’s own web browser as opposed to on a distant server. After it was introduced by Netscape in 1995, JavaScript was initially ignored by most professional programmers. It gained popularity beginning with the creation of AJAX (a technique which allows a web application to send and retrieve data from a server without interfering with the display and behavior of the existing page). Techniques for allowing JavaScript to create server-side applications were also developed, making it possible to build just about any sort of web application with the language. Because of this, David Yang, the director of a coding bootcamp that primarily focuses on JavaScript, claimed that “JavaScript is the one true language of the web.” The data analysis firm Redmonk has found JavaScript to be the most popular programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why is it that JavaScript has become so popular? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;versatility&quot;&gt;Versatility:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript works across browsers and devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;speed&quot;&gt;Speed&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is fast because its code is run immediately. This is possible because JavaScript is run on the client’s browser rather than having to contact a separate server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;simplicity&quot;&gt;Simplicity:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is simple to learn since the syntax isn’t too complex. JavaScript also has detailed libraries which contain pre-written scripts to make writing in the language easier. The following image is an example of what Javascript code looks like.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://blogs.msdn.com/cfs-filesystemfile.ashx/__key/communityserver-blogs-components-weblogfiles/00-00-00-36-44-TypeScript100112/6406.image2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image from &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/somasegar/archive/2012/10/01/typescript-javascript-development-at-application-scale.aspx/&quot; title=&quot;Somesgar&#39;s Blog.&quot;&gt;Somesgar’s Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interactivity&quot;&gt;Interactivity:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript can manipulate HTML to make web pages more interactive. For example, a “prompt’ function asks a user to type a response, then remembers it. So using this, you can ask a user “what is your name?” This allows for a better user experience. 
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.codeproject.com/KB/scripting/JavaScriptConsole/Window.prompt.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeproject.com/KB/scripting/JavaScriptConsole/Window.prompt.jpg/&quot; title=&quot;The Code Project.&quot;&gt;The Code Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;disadvantages&quot;&gt;Disadvantages?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some possible disadvantages of JavaScript, you may ask? JavaScript sometimes creates security problems since it runs on the client’s computer. It also may be interpreted differently by different browsers, but this can be avoided by testing it in all major browsers. Clearly, the disadvantages aren’t too significant since they haven’t prevented JavaScript from taking over the world!.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hallerandhug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/line-divider.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chefs in the Kitchen</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/08/cultural3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/08/cultural3</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-take-on-the-dbc-experience-what-is-your-impression-of-dbc&quot;&gt;What’s your take on the DBC experience? What is your impression of DBC?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his Fireside Chat &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/85001014/&quot; title=&quot;video&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; Shereef Bishay discusses how traditional education is served to students on a plate like a meal in a restaurant. Conversely, he discusses how DBC students are like chefs placed in the kitchen since they are the ones coming up with solutions rather than being spoon-fed them. This enmpowers students with a sense of creative ownership so that they can take control over their own education. I find DBC’s philosophy intriguing and get the impression that students acquire a great deal more practical abilities than they do in most traditional programs. I also get the sense that the DBC staff and students all encourage and inspire one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DBC doesn’t just guide students on the journey to learning to program. It also places a strong emphasis on developing empathy since being able to explain our thought processes and connect with others will be an important part of any career that we have in the future. Spending a significant amount of time pair programming not only helps us improve our technical aptitude but also gives us an opportunity to practice empathy. As someone with a psychology background, I appreciate this emphasis on developing emotional intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-do-you-see-yourself-engaging-with-this-type-of-culture&quot;&gt;How do you see yourself engaging with this type of culture?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am excited to be a part of the collaborative, supportive culture at DBC. Most of my homework in college was solo work. Even in research laboratories that I worked in, I was part of a team but spent hours at a time completing tasks on my own. As a result, pair programming is a new experience for me since we have to explain our thought process out loud step by step. I find this way of working to be stimulating and am looking forward to continuing to improve at it. I also am not used to feeling vulnerable since the classes that I took in the past came naturally to me yet computer programming doesn’t seem to to the same extent. Embracing our vulnerability is a part of the DBC culture, and it will be a valuable experience to learn how to accept this part of myself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-your-expectations-of-dbc-changed-if-so-how&quot;&gt;Have your expectations of DBC changed? If so, how?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first heard of programming bootcamps several years ago, I had an image in my head of people typing away at their computers for hours at a time with zero social interaction. Boy was I wrong! DBC has changed my expectation of bootcamps and software engineering in general in such an awesome way. I now see that DBC and what comes after are as much a social experience as technical. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-you-excited-to-participate-in-this-kind-of-learning-environment-does-it-make-you-nervous&quot;&gt;Are you excited to participate in this kind of learning environment? Does it make you nervous?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am thrilled to participate in this kind of learning environment. I am a bit nervous too because I know so little about programming, but that is part of what makes this opportunity so exciting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hallerandhug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/line-divider.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Inline vs.  Display Inline-Block</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/03/technical2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/05/03/technical2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every element on a website (i.e. a paragraph, heading, list, etc) is either displayed on a new line (block element) or on the same line as other elements (inline element). A developer must be aware of which of these displays an object will take so that they can ensure that elements appear where they would like them to. Floating and positioning are terms for processes that involve placing elements in a certain way, but using display:inline-block is another way to control where an element appears. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inline-elements&quot;&gt;Inline elements:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow other elements next to them. 
Respect left and right margins and padding, but will ignore top and bottom margins and padding and will ignore width and height settings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Examples: a, span, em, i &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;block-elements&quot;&gt;Block elements:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take up the entire line; thus, block elements create a line break and are surrounded by whitespace. 
Allow for margins and padding on all four sides. 
If no width is set, will expand to fill its parent container (the element that it is placed inside of). If no height is set, it will expand to fit its child elements (elements that are placed within the block element) if they are not floated or positioned. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Examples: p, div, header, nav, ul, li, h1 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inline-block-elements&quot;&gt;Inline-block elements:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behave like a hybrid of inline and block elements because:
Place an element on the same line as adjacent content (like an inline element)
Create a rectangular region (block) because it respects margins and padding on all four sides and can have height and width set (like a block element) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1371.photobucket.com/albums/ag309/hilaryrose/display22_zps6b7147cc.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pop quiz… Is the above photo an example of an inline, block, or in-line block element? Answer: it is an inline element since other inline elements would show up right next to it! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;floating-vs-inline-block&quot;&gt;Floating vs Inline-Block?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both floating and using inline-block let you create a grid of boxes that fill the browser width. But inline-block lets you create the same effect without having to clear the float. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hallerandhug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/line-divider.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>User Experience and Design</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/04/26/technical1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/04/26/technical1</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;cirrusmdhttpcirrusmdcom-cirrusmd-user-experience-and-design&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cirrusmd.com/&quot; title=&quot;CirrusMd&quot;&gt;CirrusMD&lt;/a&gt; User Experience and Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telemedicine website, CirrusMD, has an elegant, modern design and an intuitive user experience. It is one of my favorite websites because I adore the Twitter Bootstrap framework that it is built on, which allows for the sleek design and enjoyable interactivity. The interactive elements of the Boostrap framework, such as swiping, make visitors feel like they are engaged. Having content open within the same frame rather than redirect visitors to a separate page also prevents distraction. The simplicity of the website mirrors the purpose of the service: to make it easy to see a doctor by using videochat. A visitor’s eye is immediately drawn to the large picture of a patient booking an online session with a doctor because it takes up 60% of the page. This allows visitors to instantly grasp how simple it is to arrange an appointment without needing to use too much text to convey this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hallerandhug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/line-divider.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;myautismteamhttpmyautismteamcom-myautismteam-user-experience-and-design&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://myautismteam.com/&quot; title=&quot;MyAutismTeam&quot;&gt;MyAutismTeam&lt;/a&gt; User Experience and Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love MyAutismTeam because it uses technology to help parents of children with autism build a social network with other parents and read reviews of providers in a Yelp-like fashion. The navigation bar has the largest text on the website to draw visitors’ attention to it. The different sections are well-organized in the navigation bar, enabling a simple user experience. On the Find Parents page, the grid arrangement of different users makes it easy to find other parents to talk to. The Pinboard enables parents to visually share their stories. It is worth noting that as a visitor scrolls down, the “feedback” button remains fixed at the left, making it easy for MyAutismTeam to collect data during their beta testing. I would suggest that the “Get Started” link be placed in the top right corner of the website rather than at the end of the navigation bar because a new visitor might not notice it. A blue and white color scheme rather than blue, white, and green may be more soothing. Overall, the website is using user experience design to provide an extraordinary solution to an important problem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hallerandhug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/line-divider.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;theweekhttptheweekcom-theweek-user-experience-and-design&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theweek.com/&quot; title=&quot;TheWeek&quot;&gt;TheWeek&lt;/a&gt; User Experience and Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Week is my favorite news resource not only because of the quality of its articles but also because it organizes news by speed reading (quick reads) and most popular news items. This makes it simple for busy people to efficiently decide what to read. I especially like how the website accompanies many article titles with pictures, making it possible to skim for topics of interest without having to read any text. Because there is a significant amount of content on the website, it would improve the design to remove some of the many ads. Also, it would make more sense to place the email newsletter signup form higher on the page in case a visitor does not scroll down so low. Other advertisements are more noticeable than promotions for the magazine version of The Week, yet it is unclear whether this is intentional or not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hallerandhug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/line-divider.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Your Values</title>
      <link>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/04/26/cultural1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/2014/04/26/cultural1</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;values&quot;&gt;Values&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think of the times in my life where I’ve been the happiest, the proudest, or the most satisfied, the following are some of the values that come to mind: achievement, adventure, affection, close relationships, commitment, community, compassion, economic security, enthusiasm, excitement, freedom, friendships, having a family, helping other people, helping society, honesty, independence, inspiration, loyalty, music, nature, spirituality &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;music&quot;&gt;Music&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music is important to me not only because I have always enjoyed listening to it and playing instruments but because it has been a large part of my social life. In middle and high school, the band and orchestra were where I met many of my best friends. Hanging out in the music classrooms was always a respite for me. Incorporating music into mentoring programs I have been involved with has also allowed me to help children with special needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;live-it-up&quot;&gt;Live It Up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a scale of 1 (disagree) to 5 (agree), I agree that I try to live up to the values listed above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;advice&quot;&gt;Advice&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last topic someone asked for my advice on was their love life :-) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.hallerandhug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/line-divider.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    

  </channel> 
</rss>